哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
今天剪一点干辣椒
I'm cutting some dried chilli today
还有这个牛肉
And this beef
买了差不多10斤
Bought about 10 jin
10斤牛肉配2斤这个干辣椒
10 jin beef with 2 jin dried chilli
炒来做冷吃牛肉
I'm gonna make some Leng Chi Niu Rou
这个冷吃牛肉要凉了之后才好吃
This Leng Chi Niu Rou tastes better when cold
就让它浸泡
Let it soak
把这个油啊味道这些全部进去了之后
allow these oil and flovour to get inside
再拿来吃
then we eat it
而且这个干辣椒要剪成丝的可能味道更好一点
and these dried chilli taste better if you cut it into strips
味道可能差不多就是更好看一点
perhaps it taste the same, just looks better
我还准备了这个辣椒面
I've also got this ground chilli
辣椒面都是用两种
two types of ground chilli
就是用3种辣椒来炒
we're using 3 different types of chilli to make this dish
现在我们要用这个姜拍一下
now we crush these gingers
还有这个大葱
and scallions
等一下煮这个牛肉
cook these beef later
因为这个牛肉比较大坨
as these beef are fairly chunky
都这么大一坨
this big
总共有3大坨
and we have 3 big chunks
我估计一锅炒不完要炒两锅
I guess we'll have to cook these in two batches
煮牛肉要加一点料酒可以去下腥
when cooking beef, add a little bit of cooking wine can eliminate the taste of blood
煮这个牛肉的时候我加了点八角桂皮香叶一起
I added some star aniseeds, cinnamons and bay leaves
刚才我们这个打出的浮沫都是黑的
the froth we got out was black
黑的就是血水
that was blood
那个真的是血
like real blood
现在为什么是白的
but why it is white now
因为血水已经煮出来了
that's because the blood has came out
所以打浮沫的时候也不一定全部要打干净
so you don't necessarily have to get all the froth out
主要打到这个浮沫变成白色的就没有什么大问题
as long as the froth is white then that's fine
好了 现在我要把这个牛肉捞出来准备切一下
Ok now i'm going to take these beef out and cut them
这个牛肉已经煮了1个小时了
It has been cooked for an hour
当时说煮40分钟因为这个牛肉实在太大块
I sair 40 min, but these chunks of beef are too big
10斤牛肉煮出来缩水
once cooked, 10 jin of beef shrinks to
5斤都不到了
less than 5 jin
可能只有4斤多
perhaps a bit over 4 jin
老出来要让它凉一会儿
let it set aside to cool down for a bit
凉一会儿我们再来切 现在切的话是烫手的这个
It's too hot to hold on, let's cut it when it cools down
这个牛肉看都看得到非常紧实
you can see how firm these beefs are
现在这个牛肉已经冷得差不多但是还在冒热气
now it's almost cooled but still steaming
就把它切成粗丝
cut it into thick strips
有多粗呢大概就是筷子这么粗就对了
roughly the thickness of a chopstick
因为这个牛肉的纹路有的是横的有的是竖的
some of the grains of the beef are horizontal and some are vertical
所以我们在切的时候
so when we are cutting it
直接你怎么样子切更好久可以了
just cut it however works for you the best
可以不用去考虑它是顺的还是逆的
don't worry about whether it's along or across the grain
Meow~
待会儿姜和葱第一切大块一点
later we cut gingers and scallions in big chunks
我们炒好了之后把这2个东西挑出来
we remove these two once fried
如果放在里面的话
If we leave them in,
一是这个放久了会发酸
for one it goes sour after some time
如果这两个不挑出来这个牛肉的保质期没那么长
and the beef won't stay edible for as long
这个得话直接切成段就可以了
just cut into strips will be alright
方便更一下夹出来
easier for us to pick it out
放进去
there it goes
可以啦 下一步开始炒一下它
alright, next we stir-fry it lightly
我们这个菜油烧到它冒大烟的时候就说明已经是熟了
the Canola oil is ready once you can see smoke coming out of it
然后再放姜葱下去炸一下
then lightly stir-fry some gingers and scallions
把姜葱的香味炸出来了之后再放牛肉进去爆
bring out the aromas of gingers and scallions then add beef in it
牛肉爆到干香了之后再放干辣椒
add chiilli when the aroma of beef is brought out
再放其他它的一些调料
then add in some other ingredients
我们把这个姜葱炸到金黄了之后就要把它捞出来
strain them out once they are golden brown
少加一点花椒 一小把
add some sichuan peppercorn, just a pinch
大家听到响没有
y'all heard the sound?
响的话就说明这个牛肉里面水分还是挺重的
that means there is quite some water in the beef
这一大盆分2次炒吧1一次也炒不完
have to split it in two batches, can't really cook them all in one run
把这个牛肉里面的水份给它煸干煸香
slowly dries out the water in these beefs and brings out the flavour
现在加点这个陈皮
now let's add some mandarin peels
我们一般炒这个牛肉的时候千万不要只看颜色
generally speaking, don't estimate just by it's color
不能只看这个肉的颜色好要经常试一下
you'll need to regularly taste it out
要看它这个里面的水份
see how much water is left in it
够不够干
is it dry enough?
够干的话我们就进行下一步
move to the next step if it is dry enough
有的时候我们看这个牛肉其实已经
sometimes these beefs looks like
颜色够了但是里面还是水份不够干
they've got enough color on it, but still not dry enough
这样也是不行的
this is no good
这个牛肉已经爆得干香了
now the aroma of the beef is bought out
现在放这个辣椒
chillis in
花了一下午剪的这个辣椒
I spent my whole afternoon on cutting these chillis
真的是很不容易
That was quite some effort in it
辣椒和籽一样一半
chilli skins and seeds h
也不能只放辣椒
辣椒只管辣
这个籽的话就管香
这个有点满
我想拿起来翻一下
翻过来了
这个干辣椒下去把它爆香
爆香了之后待会儿再加一点刚才煮牛肉的原汤下去
把这个肉的味道收进去
把原汤收干了之后再放点辣椒面
然后再开始调味
我都闻到香了
加点原汤进去
刚才煮肉的原汤
然后加这个原汤的话慢慢给它收
可以把辣椒的这个香味收到肉里面去
而且还没那么燥
我们最后再加一些糖
这个口感就很不错了
现在这里面已经收干了
调下味就行了
调味的话
我们只用生抽酱油
然后白糖
加一点点醋
再放一点其他香料就可以了
放一勺
放点香料粉 花椒面
然后再放点芝麻
再抓一点点白糖
再放一点醋
好啦 这个冷吃牛肉就做好啦
现在就是关火
让它冷
现在吃的话味道是有一点
但是不是很足
如果我们炒冷吃
冷吃系列的东西
炒的时候味道已经够了
然后放一段时间你会发现
太咸了或者是太辣了
或者是说过头了
这个时候炒
炒到这个时候热的时候吃
感觉味道差那么一点点
它凉了之后
这个味道就非常的到位
好啦 我们现在等它凉一下
把它倒出来凉一下
其实加一点辣椒进去炒出来还是蛮多的